# Md. Jamil Istiaq

jamilistiaq@gmail.com Cell: 0449225808

Web: jamil-istiaq.github.io

#### **Objective**

A student, researcher, software enthusiast and an acquisitive person who is actively searching for practical knowledge to get adapted to the everchanging modern technologies, also willing to gather expertise to lead a team for the successful completion of a given project. Research interests are Data Science, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Machine Learning (ML), Computer vision (CV)

#### **Education**

University of Southern Queensland (UniSQ)

Master of Data Science (On-going)

American International University- Bangladesh (AIUB)

Bachelor of science in Computer Science and Engineering (2018 to 2022)

**CGPA 3.53** 

Award: Dr. Anwarul Abedin's Leadership AWARD at 21th Convocation.

## **Job Experiences**

• Jr Software Developer

Dekko Lagecy Group, May 2022 to August 2022

IT Officer

SEMIOTIFY, August 2022 to January 2023

#### **Projects and Thesis**

• Attendance Management System, php (Laravel, Web Application, MVC) (\*)
Employee attendance, count working hour, salary calculate, expence, leave

• **Project Management Application,** php (Laravel, Web Application, MVC, API) Create project, project task, attachment, send message

• University Club management System, C# (Windows Form Application) All club activates through the app. Like voting, notice, event, bill etc all activity.

• **Metrorail Automation System,** Web application (php, JS, AJAX, HTML, CSS) A smart ticket management system is introduced. All data and all tickets are in virtual in a record.

• **Metrorail Automation System** Web API (.Net Framework, SOLID, Four Tier architecture.) A smart ticket management system is introduced.

• **Custom CNN and filter Visualization** (tf,keras)
A custom CNN proposed model, learning filter visualization

Underwater Object Classification Using Deep Learning (Thesis)

Transfer learning, VGG16, ResNet50, Classification, TensorFlow.

Github: <a href="https://github.com/jamil-istiaq">https://github.com/jamil-istiaq</a>

Kaggle: <a href="https://www.kaggle.com/jamilistiag">https://www.kaggle.com/jamilistiag</a>

# **Extra Curriculum Activities**

IEEE HAC Assessment Committee Member

IEEE HAC (Humanitarian Activities Committee 2022)

# Office of Student Affairs (OSA) Volunteer in Charge

Office of student affairs (OSA), Since 2019

Support and guide the admission aspirants, prepare VUES data, sort student's data and store.

# Chairperson

IEEE Computer Society AIUB Student Branch Chapter (2020 to 2021) Monitor chapter's work and organize events.

#### **Software Skills**

# Engineering software

AutoCAD, MATLAB, Simulink, Proteus, Multisim.

#### Editor/Coding software

CodeBlocks, Visual Studio, VS Code, Sublime, Atom, PyCharm

## **Knowledge Skills**

#### Programming Language

ASP .Net Framework, ASP .Net Web API, Python (TensorFlow, Keras), PHP (Laravel), JavaScript, C#, C++, C, Database (SQL, MySQL, Oracle).

#### **Certificates**

## Understanding Research Methods

University of London, Coursera

# Python Data Structures

University of Michigan, Coursera

## Managing Big Data with MySQL

Duke University, Coursera

## • Speak English Professionally: In Person, Online & On the Phone

Georgia Institute of Technology, Coursera

## **Memberships**

- IEEE Student Membership (January 2018 to Present)
- IEEE Computer Society Membership (January 2020 to Present)